MATTEO CRISTIANO | CLOUD ARCHITECT

Via San Matteo 82G, 00015 Monterotondo (RM) | +39 349 2913958 | slb6113@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm 31 years old, I'm graduate in "Astronomy and Astrophysic" - at the "La Sapienza" University of Rome - and I'm specialized on dynamics of dense stellar systems and exoplanets systems. I have been for about 2 years a PHP software developer (frontend, and backend), using the Laravel framework; every day, I also used the SQL language (MySQL databases), and managed the static analysis of the code through SonarQube. The projects in which I participated were built on AWS cloud, where I also managed release pipelines (in particular, using CodePipeline, and CodeBuild). In particular, I worked on the migration to AWS (with a serverless architecture, created by myself) of an entire ETL nightly process. I worked as System Administrator and Cloud Engineer, for the ConTe.it Customer team: in this role, I managed the servers and processes built on AWS cloud, from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Jenkins), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. I also assumed the role of administrator of the company's WordPress applications. At the moment, I'm working as Cloud Architecture & Operations Expert, at Lottomatica, managing VMs, kubernetes clusters, and CI\CD processes built on AWS and Azure clouds. I am also interested in Machine Learning and Data Science topics/processes. I'm an extrovert guy, I like to work in team (more brains are better than one!), and I'm always ready to test and improve my own skills, overcoming my limits.

Ctrl - Create the roaring Impossible

CORE COMPETENCIES

- ✓ Cloud (AWS, Azure, VMWare)
- CI\CD (Azure DevOps, Jenkins, GitLab)
- Automation (Terraform, Ansbile, Packer, Puppet, AWX, Hashicorpo Vault, Bash\Powershell\Python scripting)
- Documentation (Confluence, Notion)
- ✓ Agile (Scrum, Safe)
- Kubernetes (Vanilla, EKS, AKS, Rancher, Helm, ArgoCD)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lottomatica SPA

Cloud Architecture & Operations Expert | 09 June, 2023 - Present

I'm working as Cloud Architect, for the Lottomatica Cloud team: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on Azure cloud (using Terraform), from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Azure DevOps), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. I manage creation and integration between different systems (Azure DevOps, Kubernetes, Graphana, DataBricks, ..), and Kubernetes cluster (on-prem, and AKS). I'm also involved in the creation of infrastructure, and CI\CD processes of a Data Platform project, managing the MLOps workflow.

International Platform Operations Expert | 11 April, 2022 - 08 June, 2023

I'm working as Cloud Engineer, for the Lottomatica Cloud team, in an international project: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on AWS cloud (using Terraform), from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Azure DevOps), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. I manage creation and integration between different systems (Azure DevOps, ArgoCD, Kubernetes, Graphana, SonarQube, ..), servers life cycle (via Ansible processes), and Kubernetes cluster (on-prem, and EKS). [Ansible, CloudWatch/Events/Dashboard, CI/CD. Azure DevOps, Terraform, SonarQube, Network/Security, AWS, CentOS, Ubuntu, Windows, RedHat, Git, Bash/Python/Powershell scripting, Docker/Docker Compose, Kubernetes, EKS, ArgoCD, Confluence]

ConTe.it

DevOps & Cloud Engineer | 01 April, 2020 - 10 April, 2022

I'm working as System Administrator and Cloud Engineer, for the ConTe.it Customer team: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on AWS cloud, from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Jenkins), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. Recently, I also assumed the role of administrator of the company's WordPress applications. I manage the integration between different systems (Graphana, SonarQube, Jenkins, ..), and the servers life cycle via Packer/Ansible processes. [Packer, Ansible, CodePipeline/CodeBuild, RDS/Aurora/MySQL/SQL Server, API Gateway/Lambda Functions, CloudWatch/Events/Dashboard, AWS Transfer Family/SFTP, CI/CD, Jenkins, SonarQube, WordPress Administration, Network/Security, AWS, CentOS, RedHat, Git/CodeCommit, Bash/Python scripting]

IT Developer | 18 June, 2018 - 31 March, 2020

I'm a PHP software developer (frontend, and backend), using the Laravel framework (TDD & BDD methodology, code versioning using Git and CodeCommit); every day, I also used the SQL language (MySQL databases), and managed the static analysis of the code through SonarQube. The projects in which I participated were built on AWS cloud, where I also managed release pipelines (in particular, using CodePipeline, and CodeBuild). In particular, I worked on the migration to AWS (with a serverless architecture, created by myself) of an entire ETL nightly process. [PHP, SonarQube, SQL, MySQL, Unit/E2E test, Bash shell scripting, CodePipeline/CodeBuild, ETL, DataPipeline, RDS/Aurora, Git/CodeCommit, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Laravel, AWS]

EDUCATION

2015 - 2018 | La Sapienza University of Rome

Master of Astronomy and Astrophysics - 109/110

LINKS

LinkedIn profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matteo-cristiano-20788a104

GitHub profile: https://github.com/Sennar19 GitLab profile: https://gitlab.com/slb6113 Twitter profile: https://twitter.com/slb6113

CERTIFICATIONS

2023 - HashiCorp Cloud Engineer Certifications: Terraform Associate 003

2022 - Certificate of Completion of the Google IT Support Professional Certificate